审判
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
右翼部鸣明
校对
Husky
特效
presisco
压制
我知道我妈妈做了些非常不好的事
I know my mom did something really bad.
无论母星准备如何惩治我
Whatever Homeworld has in store for me...
放马来吧
I'm ready!
我说 放马来吧
I said, I'm ready!
是我 玫瑰石英
It's me -- Rose Quartz!
喂
Hello?
有人吗
Anybody?
拉尔斯 你在哪
Lars, are you there?
这就是惩罚吗
Is this the punishment?
拜托
Come on!
我知道惩罚肯定比这要重
I know it's going to be worse than this!
所以无论你们接下来要做什么
So whatever you're gonna do...
拜托 赶紧动手吧
would you just do it already?
简直荒唐透顶
This is ridiculous!
对法庭效忠了4000年之久
4,000 years of loyal service to the court,
最后居然摊上这种倒霉事
and this is what I get?
噢 我简直是这个星系最倒霉的锆石了
Oh, I'm the unluckiest zircon in the galaxy!
等下 你是...
Wait, are you...
玫瑰石英?
Rose Quartz?
嗯
Yeah.
骗人吧
Really?
一言难尽
It's a long story.
那我可没空听你解释
Then I don't have time for it.
呃 我们就只有这片刻时间来准备你的案件
Ugh! We only have this brief moment to prepare your case.
案件
Case?
呃啊 我到底在干嘛
Ugh! Who am I kidding?!
这毫无意义
This is pointless!
我们都听说关于粉钻之死的那些流言了
We've all heard the rumors about the demise
但是我实在不能相信这些文件
of Pink Diamond, but I can't believe these files!
被一个--她自己的士兵所杀--哈
Shattered by one - of her own soldiers -- ha!
还是当着她整班随从的面
In front of her entire entourage!
还有看看你现在的样子
And look at you now!
这滑稽的伪装只会让你
That ridiculous disguise is only going to make you
看起来更有罪
look more guilty!
没关系 因为我就是有罪
That's fine, because I am!
别这么说
Well, don't say that --
尤其是等会儿你到了外面的时候
especially not when you're out there!
外面是哪? 到底会发生什么
Out where?! - What's going to happen!?
你认为会发生什么?! 玫瑰石英!
What did you think was going to happen, Rose Quartz?!
一旦那扇门一打开 你就要被审判了!
As soon as that door opens, you're going on trial!
噢
Oh.
为一个叛徒辩护?
Defending a rebel?
这是不是算 叛星罪了
Isn't that...treason?
我是被分配干这个的
I was assigned to this!
全体起立 向光辉的黄钻石致敬
All rise for the luminous Yellow Diamond!
向辉煌的蓝钻石致意
And the lustrous Blue Diamond.
被告人呢
Where is the accused?
那就是玫瑰石英吗
Is that Rose Quartz?
看她现在那丑不忍睹的形态
Look at this hideous form she's taken.
别管审判了
Forget the trial.
光是维持这种形态就应该判死罪了
We should shatter her just for looking like that.
不行 我要听她自己的申诉
No! I want to hear her make her case.
我想要知道她认为我们会怎么处置她
I want to know what she thinks we're going to do with her,
因为我想做的比那更残酷
because I want to do something worse.
行 那就让我们开始吧
Fine! Let's just get on with it, shall we?
我的钻石 我杰出的 豪富的 光芒四射的 闪烁的--
My Diamond. My brilliant, opulent, radiant, glimmering --
只要说"我的钻石"就足够了 不然我们一辈子都完成不了
"My Diamond" will suffice, or we'll never get through this.
当然 我的钻石
Of course, My Diamond.
玫瑰石英犯下如此史无前例的罪
Rose Quartz committed a crime so unprecedented
使人不得不提出疑问--为什么
that one can't help but wonder -- why?
呈上"证物"A
Exhibit "A."
拉尔斯
Lars!
史蒂文 到底发生了什么
Steven! What's going on here?!
我们在哪
Where are we?!
那些巨大的女士们又是谁
Who are those huge, giant ladies?!
正如我们从这个样品中可以看出的
As we can see from this specimen...
毫无疑问 人类是喧嚣又丑陋的生物
...humans are loud, absolutely hideous creatures
它们的存在毫无意义
that serve no purpose whatsoever.
又有什么样的宝石人会为了人类而背叛自己的同类呢
What sort of gem would turn on her own kind for this?
让我来告诉你们--就是那样的
I'll tell you what kind -- that kind.
放他走 他与案件毫无联系
Just let him go! He's got nothing to do with this!
看看--就是这样的冲动 这样的暴怒--
There it is -- the passion, the fury --
驱使残忍的玫瑰石英去
that caused the diabolical Rose Quartz to...
粉碎自己的钻石
shatter her own diamond!
我知道你们在想什么
But I know what you're thinking...
"这玩意儿可不像玫瑰石英啊"
"This thing doesn't look like a Rose Quartz."
因此 我特地叫来了一位目击证石
And for that, I would like to call an eyewitness!
哦 眼宝
Oh, Eyeball!
别给我瞎起名 你这战犯
Do not address me, war criminal!
我只是很高兴你没事
I'm just glad you're okay.
我是听她亲口说的 她说
I heard it straight from her. She said...
"我就是那个伟大的玫瑰石英"
"I'm the mighty Rose Quartz.
"我有她的盾牌啊啥的"
I've got her shield and everything."
然后她把我扔进了太空
And then she threw me into space!
我是在试着救你 我治愈了你的宝石
I tried to help you! I healed your gem!
所以说除了邪恶的
And who else has the ability
玫瑰石英 还有谁有
to heal gems other than the villainous...
治愈宝石的能力
Rose Quartz?!
所以那么我们证实了
And there you have it!
是玫瑰石英干的 而那就是玫瑰石英
Rose Quartz did it, and that's Rose Quartz.
我说完了
I rest my case.
噢 她可真棒
Oh, she's good.
嘛 我相信了 行刑吧
Well, I'm convinced! Time to execute!
还没完呢 辩护律师还得发言
Not yet. The defense still has to speak.
对啊 啊 呃
Right! Well, uh...
在我开始 我的 呃 深思熟虑的辩护之前
Before I start, my very, uh, thought-out defense,
我想要提醒法庭的各位
I'd like to remind the court
玫瑰石英确实自首了
that Rose Quartz did turn herself in.
法庭记得 法庭也不关心
The Court remembers, and the Court does not care.
呃 当然 呃 无-无辜
Uh, of course. Uh, in-- innocent!
呃 "无辜"这个词可以解释为
Uh, the word "innocent" can mean,
噢 很多东西
oh, many different things.
是我干的
I did it!
什-- 啥 啥 停下
Wha-- What, what! Stop!
不
No!
我想听她要说的内容
I want to hear what she has to say.
带我们逃出这里啊 史蒂文
Get us out of here, Steven!
呃
Uh...
为记录需要 请报上你的姓名
State your name for the record, please!
我 呃
I, um...
我是玫瑰石英…我有罪
I am Rose Quartz... and I'm guilty.
等下 不 别这么说啊
Wait! No, don't say that!
你们声称我做的那些事 都是真的
Everything you guys said I did, I did.
全部是我自己干的 我非常抱歉
And I did it by myself. I'm sorry.
我会接受你们给我的任何惩罚
I'll accept any punishment you want to give me.
只要你们放他走 不要再打地球的主意
Just let him go! And leave the Earth alone.
哈 听上去是个很标准的供认
Ha! Sounds like a solid confession to me!
是怎样的 你是怎样做的
How? How did you do it?
你是怎样粉碎粉钻的
How did you shatter Pink Diamond?
呃 嗯
Um, well...
我是在地球上 粉钻的轿子前做的
I did it on Earth in front of Pink Diamond's palanquin.
我大概是"住手" 这样
I was probably like "Stop!"
然后她说"我就不"
And she was all like, "No!"
所以我们就打了起来--我想应该是
So we fought -- I think.
然后她也许就开了几个大
And she probably did some cool moves.
我可能也放了几个炫酷的招
I probably did some cool stuff, too,
飞踢啊什么的
some jump kicks and stuff.
但我应该是深深犹豫着
But I was most likely deeply conflicted
要不要下杀手
about deciding to shatter her.
绝对是在一边痛哭着的
Definitely crying.
我可能是拿断裂极限干的
I probably had to use the Breaking Point to do it.
是一把剑
It was a sword!
你…是用一把剑…
You...shattered her...
粉碎她的
with a sword!
你的口供已经够了
That's quite enough testimony from you!
我们需要短暂的中场休息
We shall take a short recess.
你在那都在胡说些什么
What are you saying in there?!
"也许"这个 "大概"那个
"Maybe" this, "probably" that!
噢 你说"大概"是什么意思?!
Oh, what do you mean probably?!
听着 我只是
Look, I just...
实际上我不知道是怎么做的 好吗
I don't actually know how it happened, okay?
你不知道
You don't know?!
我
I...
不要挑战我的极限
Don't tumble my rocks!
现在我俩都是一根线上的蚂蚱
Both our gems are on the line!
到底是不是你干的
Did you do this or not?!
是我干的
It was me, all right!
玫瑰干了 然后我拥有她的宝石
Rose Quartz did it, and I've got her gem,
所以我就得对此负责
so I'm the one who's gotta pay for this!
你不知道是怎么发生的
You don't know how it happened.
我懂了 她们想要你解释怎么做的
I get it. There's a reason they want you to explain
是有原因的
how you did it.
因为这根本说不通!
It's because it doesn't make sense!
玫瑰石英是有缺陷的 这点我同意
Rose Quartz is flawed, I grant you.
一个浅层的宝石出于一种被误导的
A shallow strata gem who turned on her own kind
对地球和这种生物的依恋
out of a misguided attachment to a planet
而背叛了自己的同类
and creatures like these.
啥 什么
What?! Huh?!
正如钻石俯瞰地球那样明明白白
It's indisputable that as the diamond overseeing Earth,
粉钻是玫瑰石英的敌人
Pink was Rose Quartz's enemy.
杀死粉钻对玫瑰石英来说有充分的动机
Rose had everything to gain by shattering her.
但即使她想杀死粉钻
But even though she may have wanted to shatter
她做得到吗?
Pink Diamond, could she?
蓝钻陛下 为了辩护的缘故
Blue Diamond, for the purpose of this argument,
我可以呈上您的轿子吗
may I present your palanquin?
有必要吗
Is this necessary?
难道没有吗 请呈上
Isn't it? Please, proceed.
那么 就像档案记录的
Now, as the records show,
粉钻就是在一个轿子前遇刺的
Pink Diamond was shattered just outside a palanquin
就像这个一样
much like this.
目击证石称 粉钻刚踏出轿子
Witnesses said, Pink had stepped out
就前行了几步
and had taken only a few steps forward,
玫瑰石英就从正面袭击了她
when Rose attacked her from the front.
噢
Oh!
但没人关注的是"怎么做的"
The question no one seems to be asking is "how?"
我就在关注此事
I've been asking that question.
正-正-正-正如您所询问的 我的钻石
A-a-a-and right you are to ask, My Diamond!
因-因为在粉钻遇刺的时候
B-because, at the time that Pink was shattered,
玫瑰石英已经是几百年来
Rose Quartz had been a recognized threat
公认的威胁了
for several hundred years.
在粉钻的近身随从里没有玫瑰石英
There were no Rose Quartz soldiers in her entourage,
侍卫里也没有
and none in her guard.
所以 首先一个玫瑰石英
So how did a Rose Quartz,
在没有任何理由接近粉钻的情况下
with no business being anywhere near Pink Diamond,
是如何能够来到如此近身的地方呢
get so close in the first place?
粉钻她的随从呢
Where were Pink Diamond's attendants?
她的玛瑙呢 她的蓝宝石呢
Her Agates, her Sapphires?
还有她的珍珠呢
And where was her Pearl?
她们就在她身边
They were with her, of course.
她们目击了全程
They saw the whole thing!
但就没有一个看到玫瑰石英接近吗
But none of them saw Rose Quartz approach?
她的蓝宝石不会预示玫瑰的到来吗
Wouldn't her Sapphires have seen Rose Quartz coming?
她的玛瑙不会试图击退她吗
Wouldn't her Agates have tried to fight her off?
这确实很可疑
That is strange!
她一定是从她们之间溜过去了
She must have slipped past them!
就算是这样
Even if she did,
她的珍珠难道不会大声发出警告
wouldn't her Pearl have cried out in alarm,
"千万小心 我的钻石"
"Watch out, my Diamond!"
不 无论凶手是谁 她一定和粉钻关系亲密
No, whoever did this was already close to Pink Diamond,
是一个粉钻的侍卫会让其接近
someone her guards would allow to get near her,
是一个当要求停轿
someone she would listen to
粉钻会听从并走出轿子
when asked to stop her palanquin
的人
and step outside,
还是一个能够在事后掩盖真相
and someone with the authority to cover it up afterwards!
拥有无上权威的人
Someone with supreme authority!
是一个你们中间的人
Someone like one of you!
啊 请无视最后那段陈述
Uh, disregard that last statement!
我可能有点入戏太深了
I might have gotten carried away.
结案了 对吧 我的钻石
Case closed, right, My Diamond?
黄 住手 你为什么要这么做
Yellow, stop it! Why are you doing this?!
-好机会 我们快跑 -去哪
This is our chance! We gotta go! - Where?!
我们不需要听这一派胡言
We don't need to listen to this nonsense!
那里
There!
赶紧粉碎了玫瑰石英赶紧完事
Let's shatter Rose Quartz and be done with it!
你就不能控制一下你自己吗
Can't you restrain yourself?!
但这毫无意义
But this is pointless!
不 不是的
No, it's not!
快点把这玩意启动起来
Hurry up and drive this thing!
这些个疯狂的巨型妞的注意力马上就回来了
Those giant crazy chicks aren't gonna be distracted forever!
这是哪
Where is this?
母星
Homeworld.
你以为你跑得掉吗 玫瑰
Yellow Diamond: You think you can get away, Rose?
你守着那粒名为叫地球的尘埃…
You stood your ground on that little speck called Earth...
但现在你在我们的的地盘上了
but you're on our world now.